Margarita Mazo Old Believer and Molokan collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 2: Stavropol, Russia fieldwork
  - Subseries 2: 1990 research trip
    - Audio and video
      - 26 A Isai Iv. 21 maia 90, May 21, 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR151; 1 sound cassette
      - Side A: Anna Ill. 27 1990 Side B: Andr. Mikh., 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR152; Side A: Ramzueva experiment; Side B: Abakumok Andrei Mikhailovich.; 1 sound cassette
      - 28. Levokumskoe (konets) 5.90, 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR153; 1 sound cassette
      - 28 A: Levokumskoe (konets) 5.90, 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR154; 1 sound cassette
      - Stavropol, May 5, 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR155; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - Kam Balka, May 6, 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR156; DAT-2: 29. Zimushka zime, 30. Udaril chas pora rasstat'sia, 31. Tam khodil tam gulial molodoi kazachok(?), 32. 9 maia 1990 Posle sobraniia s Kochershnym Iv. Alekseevichem Pesnia # 762 O sotrudniki Very s Erevantsami(?) - dvoe muzhchin Iz Erevana pereekhali zhivut v pos. Nad(?) Okolo Stavropolia, 33. O vyi(?) chad(?) (?), 34. Vot chto ia propoveduiu Knizhitsa 8-26, 35. Khvalite Gospoda vse narody Klubnikin(?) 25, 36. Vot idet idet tsar' Maksim(?); 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - 3. Kam. Valka(?), May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR157; 10 maia 1990 2-aia ferma(?) Sara vas. Samarine s Fed. Vas. Abakumova: 1. Trava moia trava, 2. Tam shel-proshel, 3. Me(?) po ulitse maliu(?), 4. Priekhali svat(?), 5. A sudia gore, 6. Kalina moia, 7. Otche nash ty vse(?), 8. Mene gorami mene kholmami(?) (ne toskui)(?), 9. Mamochka mamocha plakat' Sare Vas! Prichit., 10. Skripuchee derevtse + prichitanie, 11. Slovami, 12. Poet, 13. Pesni; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - Stavropol, May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR158; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - Stavropol, May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR159; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - Stavropol, May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR160; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - Stavropol, May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR161; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - Stavropol, May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR162; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - Stavropol, May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR163; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - Stavropol, Kiev, May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR164; Levokumskoe, Kovishnikovsi and Kiev with Alexeev, Edward.; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - Lament analysis Nekrasovtsy, May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR165; Experiment laments, Novokumskoe, Gorina, Gulina, Nikulyshkina.; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - DAT-1, May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR166; Kamennaia Balka; 1 sound cassette
      - DAT-1 copy, May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR167; Side A: DAT-1 #16-20, Beginning of #16 is over-recorded with the beginning from DAT-2; Side B: DAT-1 #21-25.; 1 sound cassette
      - DAT-2 copy, May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR168; Side A: DAT-2 #1-6; Side B: DAT-2 #7-17.; 1 sound cassette
      - DAT-2 copy, May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR169; Side A: DAT-2 #17 (cont.)-28; Side B: DAT-2 #28 (cont.)-37.; 1 sound cassette
      - DAT-3 copy, May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR170; Side A: DAT-3 #1-10; Side B: DAT-3 #10-conversation about plach-19.; 1 sound cassette
      - DAT-3 copy, May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR171; Side A: DAT-3 #20-27; Side B: DAT-3 #28-41.; 1 sound cassette
      - DAT-4 copy, May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR172; Side A: DAT-4 #1-7; Side B: DAT-4 #7 (cont.)-12.; 1 sound cassette
      - DAT-4 copy, May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR173; Side A: DAT-4 #13-17; Side B: DAT-4 #17 (cont.)-24.; 1 sound cassette
      - DAT-5 copy, May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR174; Side A: DAT-5 #1-5; Side B: DAT-5 #6-12.; 1 sound cassette
      - DAT-5 copy, May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR175; Side A: DAT-5 #12 (cont.)-16; Side B: DAT-5 #17-23.; 1 sound cassette
      - DAT-6 copy, May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR176; Side A: DAT-6 #1-7; Side B: DAT-6 #8-14.; 1 sound cassette
      - DAT-6 copy, May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR177; Side A: DAT-6 #15-20; Side B: DAT-6 #20 (cont.)-24.; 1 sound cassette
      - DAT-7 copy, May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR178; Side A: DAT-7 #1-2 (beg.); Side B: DAT-7 #2 (cont.)-8.; 1 sound cassette
      - DAT-7 copy, May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR179; Side A: DAT-7 #9-19a; Side B: DAT-7 #19a (cont.)-23b.; 1 sound cassette
      - DAT-8 copy, May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR180; Side A: DAT-8 #1-9; Side B: DAT-8 #9 (cont.)-16.; 1 sound cassette
      - DAT-8 copy, May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR181; Side A: DAT-8 #16 (conversation)-26; Side B: DAT-8 #27-35.; 1 sound cassette
      - DAT-9 copy, May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR182; Side A: DAT-9 #1-8; Side B: DAT-9 #9-16.; 1 sound cassette
      - DAT-9 copy, May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR183; Side A: DAT-9 #17-20; Side B: DAT-9 #21-27.; 1 sound cassette
      - DAT-10 copy, May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR184; Side A: DAT-10 #1-7 Kiev; Side B: DAT-10 Kiev.; 1 sound cassette
      - Side A: Kam Valka / After sobranie Iv. Tim. Abakumov Side B: Plach, Ivan Timof Levokumskoe: Koviannikov + Tanya, May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR185; Kam. Valka -posle sobraniia + 2 singers from Armenia Ivan Timof. Ia est' istinnaia vinogr. lo? (Ioanna 15) (1/4 from end) Krichit the bride + song Ivan Tim. Siraha 15. Akakumov Nik. Other singers from Kam. Valka Koviashnikov: 1. n. 762 O sebrud(?), 2. O vy chady (?), 3. Vot chto ia propoveduiu, 4. Khvalite gospoda, 5. Vot idet tsar Maksim, 6. Ionna 15. Ia est ist. Poza, 7. "" 14 Da ne smushaetsia; 1 sound cassette
      - Stavropol Pominki Tape DAT-4, May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR186; 1 sound cassette
      - Stavropol Pominki Tape DAT 4+5 copy (cont.), May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR187; 1 sound cassette
      - DAT-5; 6 Priozernoe, May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR188; 1990 Stavropol Show(?) In CA Side A 1) Otkrovenie 2, 25 2)Ps. 33 Blagoslovaiu gospoda vo vsiakoe vremia 3) Kto eto blistaiushchii kak zaria 4) Isai, 12 I skazhesh tot den slavliu tebe Gosp. Side B 6. PS 2, 6 Ia pomazal tsaria moego nad Sionom 7 Ps. 121 Vozradovalsia ia, kogda skazali 8 Ps. 138, 7 Kuda poidu ot dukha tvoego 9. Otkr., 12 Ia obratilsia chtoby uvidet 5. Isai, 53 No on vzial na sebia nashi nemoshchi 6. Ps. 2, 6 Ia pomazal tsaria moego nad Sionom. -fragment, see side B. 10. Parapomenon, 10 I blagoslovil Davyd Gospoda... 11. Mark, 16, 15. I skazal im: idite.. 12. Isai, 53. Prizri s nebes; 1 sound cassette
      - Stavropol Pominy, May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR189; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - Laments, Stavropol, Pominy, Arzgir, May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR190; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - Kamennaya Balka, May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR191; 1 sound cassette
      - Pryguny (Los-Anzheles), May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR192; 1 sound cassette
      - Bania Ilach(?) + pesnia, May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR193; 1 sound cassette
      - Byliny, May 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR194; 1 sound cassette
    - Manuscripts
      - [Correspondence], 1990, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 2/12)
      - Molokan Stavropol notebook, May 1990, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 2/13)
      - [Partial tape index], 1990, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 3/1)
      - [Recording Old Believers at a south Russian village photo], undated, Photo printed on foam board.; 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 3/2)
      - Stavropol field notes, 1990, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 3/3)
      - [Stavropol song analysis], undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 3/4)
      - Stavropol tape indexes and transcripts, 1990-1993, 2008-2018, afc2022003_dc001; Partial tape indexes and song transcripts from Mazo's research in Stavropol, Russia in 1990. These indexes and transcripts were a work in progress, that Mazo continued to revise and enhance throughout her career.; 12 digital manuscripts (RTF, WPD, DOCX)
    - Negatives, slides, and photographic prints
      - Stavropol, 1990, 21 color slides (35mm); AFC 2022/003: PH040_001 - PH040_021 (Box 15)
      - [Stavropol], 1990, 20 color slides (35mm); AFC 2023/003: PH041_001 - PH041_020 (Box 16)
- Series 3: California and Oregon fieldwork
  Field recordings, field notes, tape indexes, and photographs from Mazo's research with United States diasporic Molokan and Old Believer communities in California and Oregon.
  - Subseries 1: March 1990 research trip
    - Audio and video
      - Prokhorov, March 17, 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR195; 1 sound cassette
      - Prokhorov, March 17, 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR196; 1 sound cassette
      - Prokhorov, Konovalov, Andy, LA, 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR197; 1 sound cassette
      - 4 Obnovl. Doma LA Spring, 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR198; 1 sound cassette
      - Bogdanov's house/Residence home, March 18-19, 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR199; 1 sound cassette
      - Residence Center LA, 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR200; 1 sound cassette
      - At Uraine, March 19, 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR201; 1 sound cassette
      - Side A: At David Uraine in the UMCA School; Side B: Samarin, Jim, 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR202; 1 sound cassette
      - Side A: LA at John Samarin; Side B: At Nazarovs, March 20, 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR203; 1 sound cassette
      - Side A: Nazaroff, LA, Brak; Side B: Freno\Kerman Kochergin, March 21, 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR204; 1 sound cassette
      - Kochergin Kerman (Fresno); Kerman at Kochergin's house, March 22, 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR205; 1 sound cassette
      - Kerman, March 23, 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR206; 1 sound cassette
      - Kerman, Kochegin, March 23, 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR207; 1 sound cassette
      - Kerman/San Francisco; Kerman Kochergin Sysoeva, March 24-25, 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR208; 1 sound cassette
      - San Francisco at Ed Samarin's, March 25, 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR209; 1 sound cassette
      - At George Samarin house: John Evseev-bass, Bill Nazaroff; podgoles, Mary Samodurov (sister of Bill)-lady's podgoles, Mary Nazaroff - the melody, George Samarin, March 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR210; 1 sound cassette
      - From Nazaroft tape collection; Parasha Kurnikova, March 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR211; 1 sound cassette
      - Parasha Kurnikova, L Angeles, recorded about 1975; From Nazaroff tape collection, March 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR212; 1 sound cassette
      - Parasha Kurnikova; From Nazaroff tape collection, March 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR213; 1 sound cassette
      - Nazaroft family (4 singers) folk songs; From Nazaroff tape collection, March 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR214; 1 sound cassette
      - Side A: Vasilii Prokhorov Mart 29, 1990 Side B: Novoi obrazi(?), March 29, 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR215; 1 sound cassette
      - Prokorov "Songs" for Paska, April 11, 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR216; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - Prokorov Bogdanovs, March 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR217; 1. Prohorov, William in Palm Springs 2. Obnovlenie doma Whittier; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - LA, March 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR218; LA at the Bogdanovs at the Uraines at the John Samarin's.; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - At John Samarin Nazara, March 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR219; At John Samarin's cont. of DAT-2; At Nazarov's.; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - [Untitled], March 20-21, 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR220; LA at the Nazarovs; Kerman, at Kochergin's.; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - Kerman-San Francisco, March 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR221; Kerman; San Francisco.; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - San Francisco, March 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR222; San Francisco.; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
    - Manuscripts
      - California Molokans field notes, March 1990, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 3/5)
      - California tape indexes and transcripts, 1992, 2004-2020, afc2022003_dc001; Partial tape indexes and song transcripts from Mazo's research in California in March 1990. These indexes and transcripts were a work in progress, that Mazo continued to revise and enhance throughout her career.; 15 digital manuscripts (WPD, DOCX, RTF)
      - [Nazarov collection of tapes index], undated, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 3/6)
  - Subseries 2: August 1990 research trip
    - Audio and video
      - California (master), August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR223; 1 sound cassette
      - California (master), August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR224; 1 sound cassette
      - California (master), August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR225; 1 sound cassette
      - California (master), August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR226; 1 sound cassette
      - California (master) Nazarev, August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR227; 1 sound cassette
      - California (master), August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR228; 1 sound cassette
      - California (master), August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR229; 1 sound cassette
      - California (master), August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR230; 1 sound cassette
      - California (master) Bill Prokhorev, August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR231; 1 sound cassette
      - California (master), August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR232; 1 sound cassette
      - California (master) George Samarin, August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR233; George Samarin - koleno - viliushki 2 udara Slushaet Stavropolskikh half-notes; 1 sound cassette
      - California (master), August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR234; Vasilii Ivan. Sysoev "vidat'sia"; 1 sound cassette
      - California (master) Jim Samarin, August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR235; 1 sound cassette
      - California (master), August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR236; 1 sound cassette
      - California (master), August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR237; 1 sound cassette
      - California (master), August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR238; 1 sound cassette
      - California (master), August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR239; 1 sound cassette
      - California (master), August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR240; 1 sound cassette
      - Side A: Nik. Kazarov (voprosy?) Side B: Krodo(?) Kopgrov(?) M(?), August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR241; 1 sound cassette
      - California (master), August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR242; 1 sound cassette
      - California (master), August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR243; 1 sound cassette
      - California (master), August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR244; 1 sound cassette
      - California (master), August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR245; 1 sound cassette
      - California (master), August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR246; 1 sound cassette
      - California (master), August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR247; 1 sound cassette
      - California (master), August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR248; 1 sound cassette
      - Oregon, August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR249; 1 sound cassette
      - Oregon, August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR250; 1 sound cassette
      - Oregon Biruken, August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR251; 1 sound cassette
      - Oregon Nazarov, August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR252; 1 sound cassette
      - [Untitled], August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR253; 1 sound cassette
      - LA, Palm Springs, August 9, 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR254; Nazarov, Prokhorov, with Shchetinin at Mikey Kalpakoff.; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - California, August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR255; LA (La Habra) with Shchetinins, George Samarin, Jim Samarin.; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - California, August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR256; Jim Samarin, LA, Fresno, Kerman, San Francisco (Kositsyn), Oregon, Woodburn (Komovala).; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - California, August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR257; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - Oregon, August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR258; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - California, August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR259; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - Nazarov Prokherev, undated, AFC 2022/003: SR260; Side A: LA Montebello, M. Nazarov; Side B: Palm Springs, Bill Prokhorov, solovei, molitva.; 1 sound cassette
      - Prokherev, undated, AFC 2022/003: SR261; Bill Prokhorev, molitva vs 2 and 3 ostanev, Mickey Kalpakoff.; 1 sound cassette
      - Nazarovs; Jim Samarin and Co., undated, AFC 2022/003: SR262; 1 sound cassette
      - At George Samarin, undated, AFC 2022/003: SR263; 1 sound cassette
      - Jim Samarin, undated, AFC 2022/003: SR264; 1 sound cassette
      - Jim Samarin, Frescno, Kocits, undated, AFC 2022/003: SR265; 1 sound cassette
      - Oregon. Konovalov Birukov, undated, AFC 2022/003: SR266; N1-brak na kopii (?) I dal'she v raznykh mestakh; 1 sound cassette
      - Kochergin family + Shafter group, August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR267; Kochergin family and Shafter Group copied from Kochergin's tape (reel 1).; 1 sound cassette
      - Volkoff, Kochergin's reel 2, side A, August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR268; Copied from Kochergin's tape reel 2, side A and beginning of side B. Mr. Volkoff and Mr. Neveroff group. Kochergin's note: "Beginning of side 2, 1/3 of the way is a different kind of singing. Vera's aunt (Vera=Kochergin's wife) is singing Pod-Ma-Los-Way" (Podgolos)." Sides 1 and 2 could be mixed up during copying.; 1 sound cassette
      - Kochergin's reel 2, side B, August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR269; 1 sound cassette
      - Kochergin family reel 3, August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR270; 1 sound cassette
      - Kochergin reel 4, side A, August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR271; Copied from Kochergin's tape collection, reel #4. Shafter group, Kochergin family (side B), Neveroff group (no. 23+) 677. Sides A and B could be mixed up during copying.; 1 sound cassette
      - Kochergin reel 4, side B, August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR272; Copied from Kochergin's reel 4, side B(?). Sides A and B could be confused during copying.; 1 sound cassette
      - Kochergin tape collection, August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR273; Copied from a cassette given by Ivan Kochergin in Fresno (Bill Ghosoph? Spevka, Butchkot Church). Side B: 547-672-658?-144-33-525-415-524.; 1 sound cassette
      - Kochergin's cassette, August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR274; Copied from a cassette from Kochergin tape collection, Fresno. Friends singing.; 1 sound cassette
      - Andrei Mikh. Abakumov, undated, AFC 2022/003: SR275; Vas. Vas. Prokhorovu ot Andreia Mikhail. Abakumova; 1 sound cassette
      - Kostrikin - II, III from Ed Samarin, undated, AFC 2022/003: SR276; 1 sound cassette
      - Kostrikin - IV, V from Ed Samarin, undated, AFC 2022/003: SR277; 1 sound cassette
      - Oregon copy, August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR278; 1 sound cassette
      - Oregon copy, August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR279; 1 sound cassette
      - Oregon copy, August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR280; 1 sound cassette
      - Ko(?) Eretik, Lazarev(?), undated, AFC 2022/003: SR281; 1 sound cassette
      - [Untitled], undated, AFC 2022/003: SR282; 1 sound cassette
      - Prygun Molokans - Los Angeles, Uraine's tape, undated, AFC 2022/003: SR283; From Molokans Home Library; 142 idu k Bogu 145 Vy poslushaite 157 U Davida 704 Den Gos. (sisters) 39 Khrabykh voiny Amazing Grace 120 1/2 Liubim My Otche nash 602 Zhizn' Bog. 16 H Kuda letish 132 Gos. Prebud' 415 Bog pomoshch 175 Gos. Bozhe 127 Zrite voiny 1 Pust ko 610 Khorosh Sion 33; 1 sound cassette
      - Volkoff/Neveroft, undated, AFC 2022/003: SR284; From Molokans Home Library; 1 sound cassette
      - Copy from Bill Berokoff (Woodburn) Volkov, 3 general +Volkov, undated, AFC 2022/003: SR285; From Molokans Home Library; 1 sound cassette
      - Gava(?) (?), 1952, AFC 2022/003: SR286; From Molokans Home Library; 1 sound cassette
      - Reform Church, Sobranie, August 1990, AFC 2022/003: SR287; From Molokans Home Library. Church, Oregon.; 1 sound cassette
      - Isai Iv. Koveshnikov #1 Pesni (Koveshn.), undated, AFC 2022/003: SR288; From Molokans Home Library; 1 sound cassette
      - Isai Iv. Koveshnikov #1 Psalmy, undated, AFC 2022/003: SR289; From Molokans Home Library; 1 sound cassette
      - Isai Iv. Koveshnikov #1a Psalmy (prodolzh.), undated, AFC 2022/003: SR290; From Molokans Home Library; 1 sound cassette
      - Rostovskie, undated, AFC 2022/003: SR291; From Molokans Home Library; 1 sound cassette
      - Koveshnikovy Psalmy, undated, AFC 2022/003: SR292; From Molokans Home Library; 1 sound cassette
      - Koveshnikovy / pesni, undated, AFC 2022/003: SR293; From Molokans Home Library; 1 sound cassette
      - Lecture Ancient Russian music, August 28, 1980, AFC 2022/003: SR294; From Molokans Home Library. Complete lecture on ancient Russian music, in Russian, by a Soviet prof. of music who taught in Moscow. Compliments of George John Samarin.; 1 sound cassette
      - Molokan, undated, AFC 2022/003: SR295; From Molokans Home Library; 1 sound cassette
      - Bill Berokoff and Ismi Shubin, undated, AFC 2022/003: SR296; From Molokans Home Library; 1 sound cassette
      - William Berokoff, undated, AFC 2022/003: SR297; From Molokans Home Library; 1 sound cassette
      - Columbus/Uraine, 1991, AFC 2022/003: SR298; From Molokans Home Library; 1 sound cassette
      - Uraine, Columbus, 1991, AFC 2022/003: SR299; From Molokans Home Library; 1 sound cassette
    - Manuscripts
      - California DAT recordings, August 1990, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 3/7)
      - California field notes, August 1990, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 3/8)
      - California tape indexes, 1992, 2003-2020, afc2022003_dc001; Partial tape indexes from Mazo's work in California in August 1990. These indexes were a work in progress, that Mazo continued to revise and enhance throughout her career.; 9 digital manuscripts (WPD, DOCX, RTF)
      - [Correspondence], 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 3/9)
      - [Field notes] (1 of 2), August 1990, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 3/10)
      - [Field notes] (2 of 2), August 1990, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 4/1)
      - [Index from SR284], August 1990, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 4/2)
      - Molokans, California, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 4/3)
      - Molokan U.S. [field notes], 1990, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 4/4)
      - [Partial Oregon tape index], August 1990, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 4/5)
      - [Transcript for Califo.890-Sony11 (SR233)], August 1990, 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 4/6)
    - Negatives, slides, and photographic prints
      - California, March 1990, 21 color slides (35mm); AFC 2022/003: PH043_001 - PH043_021 (Box 16)
      - California Molokans, March 1990, 2 color slides (35mm); AFC 2022/003: PH042_001 - PH042_002 (Box 16)
      - California and Oregon, August 1990, 1 color print (5x7 in.); 34 color prints (4x6 in.) (Box 12)
      - Nekrasovtsy, 1990, 8 color prints (3.5x5 in.) (Box 12)
      - [With a Molokan elder during fieldwork, Oregon photo], 1992, Photo printed on foam board; 1 folder of manuscript materials (Box-folder 4/7)
  - Subseries 3: December 1993 research trip
    - Audio and video
      - Oregon, 1993, AFC 2022/003: SR300; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - Reform Church Woodburn, Oregon, December 19, 1993, AFC 2022/003: SR301; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - Oregon/California, 1993, AFC 2022/003: SR302; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - California, 1993, AFC 2022/003: SR303; 1 sound cassette (DAT)
      - Woodburn, Konovalov, Jacob Petrovich, December 15, 1993, AFC 2022/003: SR304; 1 sound cassette
      - Woodburn, Konovalov, Shabin, December 15, 1993, AFC 2022/003: SR305; 1 sound cassette
      - Woodburn Bogdanov, December 15, 1993, AFC 2022/003: SR306; 1 sound cassette
      - Woodburn, Berokoff, December 16, 1993, AFC 2022/003: SR307; 1 sound cassette
      - Woodburn, Berokoff, December 16, 1993, AFC 2022/003: SR308; 1 sound cassette
      - Berokoff, December 1993, AFC 2022/003: SR309; 1 sound cassette
      - Woodburn, Vera Grigoriev, December 17, 1993, AFC 2022/003: SR310; 1 sound cassette
      - Wood vigi.(?) Grigor'eva / chisto(?), December 1993, AFC 2022/003: SR311; 1 sound cassette
      - Woodburn, Grigorleva Vera, Jim, December 17, 1993, AFC 2022/003: SR312; 1 sound cassette
      - Woodburn, December 17, 1993, AFC 2022/003: SR313; 1 sound cassette
      - Woodburn Nazarov, December 18, 1993, AFC 2022/003: SR314; 1 sound cassette
      - Woodburn, Nazarov Lube, December 18, 1993, AFC 2022/003: SR315; 1 sound cassette
      - Woodburn, Kapssov, December 18, 1993, AFC 2022/003: SR316; 1 sound cassette
      - Kochergin, December 1993, AFC 2022/003: SR317; 1 sound cassette
      - Kochergin, December 1993, AFC 2022/003: SR318; 1 sound cassette
      - Fresno Kochergin, 1993, AFC 2022/003: SR319; 1 sound cassette
      - Madeira/Gusev, 1993, AFC 2022/003: SR320; 1 sound cassette